Short-Run University Publications UP194
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Short-Run University Publications
1870 -- 2013
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts University
UP194
1.5 Linear Feet
This collection includes a variety of university publications that were only published briefly.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Biographical / Historical
Since 1955, Tufts University has continued to expand its horizons. In 1964, in one of Wessell's final acts as president, Tufts opened the Experimental College. The Ex-College, which allows students to take classes not normally found in the curriculum, has remained one of Tufts' most popular programs.
In 1977, Tufts established a five-year joint degree program with the New England Conservatory of Music. Soon after, in 1979, a similar program began with the School of the Museum of Fine Arts. Also in 1979, the Tufts Center for European Studies in Talloires, France, was established in an 11th Century priory. The Tufts European Center began operation soon after.
In late 1979, Tufts made another important addition. In October, the Tufts University School of Veterinary Medicine opened at its original Boston campus. In 1980, the Grafton campus, built on the site of a state mental hospital, officially opened its doors.
The last two major additions to Tufts University took place in 1980 and 1981. In 1980, the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, established with a large grant from the Sackler family, opened its doors on the Boston campus of the Tufts School of Medicine. In 1981, at the Medford Campus, Tufts celebrated the opening of the School of Nutrition Science and Policy. The school was the first of its kind in the nation.
Since Tufts College was officially established in 1852, it has continued to grow and expand in new directions. From its beginnings as a small liberal arts college through its expansion into a full-scale university, Tufts has maintained a strong academic tradition and a community feel.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes a variety of university publications that were only published briefly. Publications include magazines and newsletters from various departments of the undergraduate and graduate schools, including course catalogs, maps, brochures of the different programs for prospective students, newsletters on department research and developments for alumni, faculty, staff and/or students.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
- Short-Run University Publications, 1870 -- 2013; UP194.001; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This collection includes all short-run university publications.
  Arrangement
  This collection is not arranged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts Nutrition, 1999 -- 2000; UP194.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Career Services, 1999; UP194.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Course Listings and Admissions Advertisement, 1870 -- 1960; UP194.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Campus Maps and Guides, UP194.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - One Hundred Honors, 2000; UP194.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Bulletin of the School of Engineering, 1900 -- 1998; UP194.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - CEM Review, 1992; UP194.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Sun on the Hill II News: Tufts Solar Vehicle Project, 1991; UP194.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Laboratory, Chemical and Biological Safety Manual, 1993; UP194.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    School of Veterinary Medicine
  - Arts and Sciences Information Bookley, 1991 -- 1992; UP194.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Arts and Sciences Faculty Handbook, 1979; UP194.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Asbestos Information Center Course Bulletin, 1988 -- 1989; UP194.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Host Advisor Manual, 1984; UP194.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - First-Year Advising for the Class of 2002, 1998; UP194.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Information for Entering Students, 1974 -- 1975; UP194.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Plans for Pre-Freshman Seminar, 1941 -- 1963; UP194.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Summer of Service, 1993; UP194.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Guide to Winter Studies, 1973 -- 1974; UP194.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Medical Student Newsletter, November, 1982; UP194.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Tufts News, Vet School, 1986 -- 1987; UP194.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Referral Guide, Hospital for Large Animals, 1991; UP194.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - CFAST, Dept. of Chemistry, 1996; UP194.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - New England Environmental Conference News, 1996; UP194.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Green Works Bulletin, 1992 -- 1993; UP194.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - School of Nutrition News for Alumni, 1987; UP194.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - The Arts at Tufts, 1990; UP194.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Dance News and Notes, 1986 -- 1987; UP194.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - HNRC News, 1991 -- 1992; UP194.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Medical School Postgraduate Course Listing, 1946 -- 1957; UP194.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Medical School Secondary Application, 1998; UP194.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Medical and Dental Library Guide, 1977; UP194.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - This Week, NE Medical Center, 1989; UP194.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Medical School, By-laws of the Faculty, 1994; UP194.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Medical School Papers, 1940; UP194.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Medical Student Directory, 1973 -- 1974; UP194.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Music, 1996; UP194.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Koleinu - our voice, 2002; UP194.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - History department newsletter, 1997; UP194.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Fletcher perspectives, Spring, 2002; UP194.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Junior electives booklet, School of Veterinary Medicine, 1984; UP194.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Don't Panic... Read This, June, 1989; UP194.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
    An irregular bulletin of the Public Access, Networking & Information Committee.
  - Innovation in Learning, 2002-09 -- 2003-02; UP194.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
    Academic Technology at Tufts
  - TPS Report, Newsletter of the Tufts Psychology Society, Spring and November, 2003; UP194.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Innovation in Learning, April, 2003; UP194.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - The Trumpet: Getting to know the Faculty, Administrators, and Staff at Tufts, 1995; UP194.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
    Reading Room copy also.
  - The Alumni News, spring, 1997; UP194.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - The Charles Tufts Society News, Spring, 1993; UP194.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
    Volume, issue
    3, 1
  - The Charles Tufts Society News, Spring, 1994; UP194.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
    4, 1
  - H S Links, 1997; UP194.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Outlook: continuing studies and summer programs at Tufts, fall, 1996; UP194.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Hooper Health Beat, UP194.001.002.00034 (Box 2)
    4, 3
  - The Tufts Prospect, March, 1962; UP194.001.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Faculty-Student Newsletter, 1969 -- 1970; UP194.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - The Medium, 1970; UP194.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Medical School, Newsletter (Continuing education), 1970 -- 1972; UP194.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - NEMC Administrator's Newsletter, 1966 -- 1969; UP194.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - NEMC The Cancer Institute Bulletin, 1963 -- 1982; UP194.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - NEMC Dimensions, 1968 -- 1969; UP194.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - NEMC In-Crowd, 1969 -- 1971; UP194.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - NEMC In-Crowd, 1971 -- 1974; UP194.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - NEMC The Reporter, 1993 -- 1994; UP194.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - NEMC Update, 1979 -- 1981; UP194.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Tufts New England Newsletter, 1977 -- 1978; UP194.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - NEMC This Week, 1985 -- 1991; UP194.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - NEMC Report, 1970 -- 1971; UP194.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - History from the Hill, Newsletter of the History Department at Tufts University, February/March, 2004; UP194.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Tufts Neighborhood News, 1987; UP194.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Tufts International Research Center, May, 1990; UP194.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Tufts Entrepreneur, September, 2004; UP194.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
    Young entrepreneurs at Tufts.
  - Citizen Participation, 1982; UP194.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
    Publication of the Lincoln Filene Center.
  - Jumbo Robust, Spring, 2005; UP194.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
    Tufts wellness coalition newsletter.
    1, 1
  - Tufts University Environmental Programs, 1990; UP194.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
    Booklet is undated. Noted on cover: "DISPLAY ONLY! Call 627-3394 for copies".
  - Graduate News, 2008 -- 2009; UP194.001.003.00021; Office of Graduate Studies (Box 3)
    Possible successor publication to Graduate Matters.
  - Graduate News, 2009 -- 2010; UP194.001.003.00022; Office of Graduate Studies (Box 3)
  - The Budget, 1874-02; UP194.001.003.00023; Theta Delta Chi (Box 3)
    Publication produced by Kappa Chapter of Theta Delta Chi. Contains essays, anecdotes, poetry, class officer information, school groups, and artwork.
  - The Budget, 1875; UP194.001.003.00024; Theta Delta Chi (Box 3)
  - Graduate News, 2010 -- 2011; UP194.001.003.00025; Office of Graduate Studies (Box 3)
  - Graduate News, 2012 -- 2013; UP194.001.003.00026; Office of Graduate Studies (Box 3)
  - ISIP Year End Newsletter, 2012-05-07; UP194.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Tufts Greek Focus, 2012; UP194.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
    1, 2
  - The Fletcher Folio, 1976 -- 1977; UP194.001.004.00001 (Box 4)